Rosanne Anderson

Software Engineer

410-404-8831 Baltimore, MD

anderson.rosanne4@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/rosanne-anderson/

https://github.com/RosanneE

https:/RosanneAnderson.com

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING EXPERIENCE

Teaching Assistant / General Assembly

December 2022-Present

- Provides educational support for the Software Engineering Immersive course
- Teaches current coding topics including: JavaScript, HTML and CSS fundamentals; Node and Express; Database creation and management; API integrations; Python, Django, and React
- Debugs code and teaches problem solving skills to increase student independence and tests student code through manual testing of their applications, to ensure projects meet assignment requirements
- Troubleshoots downloading and installing programs & packages and web deployment
- Coaches students on workload management and post-graduation options
- Collaborates with instruction team to meet the needs of students and advocates for students who need more coaching, or additional challenges

Sprint Participant - Project Manager & SEI Developer / The Opportunity Project May 2023- Present

- Leads a team of 15+ Software Engineers, UX/UI Designers, and Data Scientists/Analysts on The Opportunity Project, led by the US Census Bureau, the US Department of Commerce, and the FDA.
- Uses federal data to build an application focused on tracking Covid-19 testing
- Creating a white labeled website to enable local groups to better motivate their communities to participate in tracking efforts
- Instituted and works with team leads to insure information sharing, collaboration and a smooth development process between UX/UI, SEI, and Data teams
- Works with mentors from the US Census Bureau, the US Department of Commerce, and the FDA to gain profession insight on current solutions to inform our build

Technical Resources Manager/ Rye of Baltimore

February 2021-December 2022

- Updates the company website and adds new features/components (using Wordpress, CSS, HTML, and JavaScript) and checks to ensure quality and usability of site
 - Creates Social Media content, photographs events, uses Canva and other tools for posts
- Created updated system for tracking expenses between sister businesses using Excel
- Preformed IT duties for all restaurant technology
- Assisted in creating and running bar events, & acted as the contact point for clients and vendors

General Assembly / Software Engineering Immersive March 2022-June 2022

A 12 week, 600+ hour software engineering course that provides classes and hands on experience with front and back end programming. I learned how to use multiple frameworks and stacks to develop web applications, and as part of the course created 3 full stack applications (1 within a team) from the ground up. I also gained experience with third-party APIs, practiced Leet Code and other algorithmic challenges, worked with multiple databases, and deployed both front ends and back ends on appropriate platforms.

Programing Languages: Python, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, JQuery, Node.js, Java, Swift

Database: Django, SQL, PSQL, SQLite, MongoDB

Other Tools: Express, React, Flask, Heroku, Netlify, Visual Studio Code, Eclipse, Emacs,

GitHub, CodePen, Jest, Mocha

Projects: Cocktail Menu Creator, Color Selector React Website, Reverse Engineered

Website, Minesweeper Game

Additional Computer Science Education:

- UMBC Computer Science Program, January 2015-December 2015
- University of Maryland College Park Computer Science Program, January 2014-December 2014
- Code Academy: Learn JavaScript Unit Testing, Learn BootStrap
- Udemy: JavaScript Unit Testing The Practical Guide(in progress)
- Tutorialspoint: Java Tutorial, Swift Tutorial

OTHER PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Data Analytics & Project Management:

Assured Partners/ December 2021-March 2022 (contract)

- Verified and populated data sets in Excel
- Created excel formulas to verify accuracy of data
- Monitored team to ensure timeliness and accuracy of submissions

Executive HR & Facilities Administrator:

Brighter, Stronger Foundation, through Ajilon Staffing Agency/ June 2020-October 2020

- Hiring and employee management
- Post open positions on internal and external platforms
- Sort resumes, interviewing applicants, create offer letters, run background checks and drug tests, employee credentialing, orientation, benefit set up,
- Ran weekly meetings to coordinate new hires between the admin and clinical staff
- Incident Investigations, create action plans/PIPs, terminating employees, unemployment reports and filings
- Covid tracking/Injuries/Workers Compensation:
 - Help create company covid tracing and best practices (including sanitation stations and signage)
 - Tracked employees who were exposed to/had covid and made sure all company policies were followed to reduce chances of an outbreak, ensured proper paperwork is filed
 - Work with supervisors and management to ensure that necessary coverage is maintained
 - Maintaining communication with employees to ensure smooth transitions back into work
- Ran Open Enrollment
- Supervised Office Manager & Clinical Employee Staffing
- Updated the company handbook
- Wrote monthly company newsletter
- Created and led employee education classes to clarify and updated procedures for supervisors and managers

Human Resources Generalist: Freshly, through Custom Staffing/ April 2020-May 2020

- Temporary HR liaison assisting temporary nursing team.
- Ensure employee compliance with company and federal covid guidelines
- Assist with open enrollment
- Communicate with multilingual employees using google translate to aid communication

Acting Human Resources Director, Human Resources Administrator: Atlantic Realty Group/ July 2017-October 2019

- Onboard new hires: Creating offer letters, running background checks and drug testing, employee credentialing, orientation, following up on employees at 30-60-90 days, and benefit set up
- Employee growth: Recommending internal candidates for promotions, creating action plans for employees in need of direction, writing up disciplinary documents, connecting employees with other team members for additional training/mentorshipAaaa
- Termination: Recommending termination for employees with ongoing behavior issues, writing up termination paperwork, terminating employees, ensuring terminated employee access is removed, unemployment reports and filings
- Injuries/Workers Compensation: Completing all workers comp forms, ensuring that
 employees complete necessary paperwork, working with employees to get
 doctors notes and drug testing, working with supervisors to ensure light duty or
 other modifications to work are implemented properly, working with management
 to ensure coverage if extended time off is required, maintaining communication
 with employees to ensure smooth transitions back into work
- Incident investigation: Writing up and investigating employee incidents, interviewing employees involved, working with law enforcement as needed, speaking to lawyers for additional advice as necessary, presenting findings and recommendations
- Payroll Administration: Running payroll and completing budgetary journal entries, balancing payroll spreadsheets, creating reports for budgeting and analytics.
 Payroll occurs biweekly, for approximately 90 employees, running between \$ 95,000 and \$120,000 per payroll, depending on bonuses, commissions, etc.
- Presenting employee education classes including topics such as recruitment, interviewing & procedural skills
- Working with the Marketing & Training Coordinator to ensure new hires received proper training both in company wide policies and in their specific fields
- Updating employee records & maintaining confidentiality with employee information
- Assisting in benefits negotiations and managing open enrollment for employees

Special projects:

- Updated a 10 year old payroll journal entry system, increasing accuracy, transparency, and efficiency. This project was completed using Excel, and allowed the company Comptroller, Vice President, and President to have a more nuanced view of payroll costs and accounting.
- Worked with Maryland Multi Housing Association on an apprenticeship program for maintenance technicians

Administration: Jones Networking/ April 2016-July 2017

- Updated inventories for accurate and detailed warehouse records
- Scheduled OSHA & company safety checks at facilities
- Scheduled deliveries to insure timely and accurate orders were received by clients
- Received payments from clients and submitted work order reports

University of Maryland Baltimore County & College Park/ Student, secretary, file clerk / January 2014-December 2015

- While attending UMBC & CP I studied computer science and worked in different administrative functions at each school. Projects included:
- Auditing expense reports and verifying purchases
- Digitizing hard copies of sensitive data to protect the integrity of files
- Performing secretarial duties for the Graduate School at UMBC

Administrative Assistant: Lifebridge Health / March 2011-November 2013

- Scheduled, coordinated, and assisted in preparations for appointments, staff meetings, donor meetings, and fundraising galas
- Created and prepared brochures, marketing flyers, pamphlets, schedules, and other materials for meetings and events
- Trained and oriented new staff members

Grassroots Marketing Manager: Dalmatian Corporation/ 2010-2011

- Planned and executed a marketing campaign to increase the visibility of the brand's dance shoes at dance events throughout the nation.
- Ran the grassroots marketing program through mailings, contests, coordination with event planners and local dance scenes.
- Cultivated new client contacts and maintained relationships with clients and brand ambassadors.

EDUCATION

General Assembly Software Engineering Bootcamp / Completion Certificate

February 2022-June 2022

McDaniel College / B.A. English & Secondary Education

August 2004 - May 2008, Westminster, MD